export const INFOCOMMTECHA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The act of converting data into information is known as data",
A: "analysis.",
B: "collection.",
C: "processing.",
D: "transformation.",
answer: "C. processing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following systems can help a user to select a product?",
A: "Decision Support System",
B: "Management Information System",
C: "Office Automation System",
D: "Transaction Processing System",
answer: "A. Decision Support System",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The technology and the system that uses computers and telecommunications to process information is called",
A: "computer engineering.",
B: "computer technology.",
C: "information technology.",
D: "telecom engineering.",
answer: "C. information technology.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The symbol that precedes a number to make it a label in spreadsheet application is the",
A: "quote sign.",
B: "equal to sign",
C: "underscore sign.",
D: "apostrophe sign.",
answer: "D. apostrophe sign.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following applications is made up of cells?",
A: "Spreadsheet",
B: "Word processor",
C: "Presentation package",
D: "Communication software",
answer: "A. Spreadsheet",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The link between the power outlet and the power supply unit of a computer is called power",
A: "bank.",
B: "cord.",
C: "pack.",
D: "switch.",
answer: "B. cord.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The time lapse between an enquiry and feedback is called",
A: "average time.",
B: "real time.",
C: "response time.",
D: "transit time.",
answer: "C. response time.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Magnetic disk data is organized on the platter in concentric sets called",
A: "block.",
B: "head.",
C: "sector.",
D: "track.",
answer: "D. track.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A list of instructions used by a computer is called",
A: "flowchart.",
B: "processing.",
C: "program.",
D: "text.",
answer: "C. program.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. An opening in a system unit where expansion cards can be inserted is known as",
A: "expansion board.",
B: "expansion port.",
C: "expansion slot.",
D: "extension box.",
answer: "C. expansion slot.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A program that assists in the maintenance of the computer is referred to as",
A: "application.",
B: "malware.",
C: "spooling,",
D: "utility.",
answer: "D. utility.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The structure of statements in QBASIC is referred to as",
A: "algorithm.",
B: "grammar.",
C: "strings.",
D: "syntax.",
answer: "D. syntax.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following commands is not executable?",
A: "INPUT",
B: "LET",
C: "PRINT",
D: "REM",
answer: "D. REM (REM is a remark or comment statement, not executable.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A group of computers connected together to enable users to communicate and share resources is called",
A: "firewall.",
B: "Netware.",
C: "network.",
D: "web",
answer: "C. network.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The database model that uses tables with columns and rows is called",
A: "hierarchical database.",
B: "linear database.",
C: "network database.",
D: "relational database.",
answer: "D. relational database.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following packages is required on a computer for a payroll software to work effectively?",
A: "Database package",
B: "Presentation package",
C: "Desktop publishing package",
D: "Word processing package",
answer: "A. Database package",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A digital sign can be represented by",
A: "letters.",
B: "octal digit.",
C: "binary digit.",
D: "special characters.",
answer: "C. binary digit.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Information overload refers to",
A: "complete information.",
B: "concise information.",
C: "reliable information.",
D: "unusable information.",
answer: "D. unusable information.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following acts is not a cybercrime?",
A: "Encryption.",
B: "Hacking.",
C: "Phishing.",
D: "Identity theft.",
answer: "A. Encryption. (Encryption is a security measure, not a cybercrime.)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The most appropriate package that can be used to design a student identity card is",
A: "FoxBase",
B: "Word Pad",
C: "MS Access",
D: "Adobe PageMaker",
answer: "D. Adobe PageMaker",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following formulas will display the current minutes past the hour of the clock in a spreadsheet application?",
A: "= MINUTE ()",
B: "= MINUTE (NOW ())",
C: "= MINUTE (YEAR ())",
D: "= MINUTE (HOUR (NOW ()))",
answer: "B. = MINUTE (NOW ())",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The process of copying data from a memory location is called",
A: "downloading.",
B: "controlling.",
C: "reading.",
D: "writing.",
answer: "C. reading.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The main input device for textual data having several keys for special functions is",
A: "keypad.",
B: "card reader.",
C: "optical character reader.",
D: "magnetic ink character recognition.",
answer: "A. keypad.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Installing a new device in a running computer requires",
A: "disassembling the computer.",
B: "installing disk operating system.",
C: "checking the device manufacturer.",
D: "determining the available resources.",
answer: "D. determining the available resources.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following features is not in a spreadsheet application?",
A: "Ability to produce charts",
B: "Mail merging a proforma letter",
C: "Capability of making accurate calculations",
D: "Files are easily re-opened, re-used and updated",
answer: "B. Mail merging a proforma letter (Mail merging is typically a feature of word processing software.)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The absolute path to a system file on a computer starts from the",
A: "compact disc",
B: "flash drive.",
C: "floppy disk.",
D: "hard disk.",
answer: "D. hard disk.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following software co-ordinates the interaction of computer devices?",
A: "Browser",
B: "Firmware",
C: "System software",
D: "Application software",
answer: "C. System software",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A good algorithm must be",
A: "brief and complex.",
B: "detailed and infinite.",
C: "sequential and robust.",
D: "consistent and ambiguous.",
answer: "C. sequential and robust.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following symbols is used to represent a sequence in a program flowchart?",
A: "Arrow",
B: "Circle",
C: "Diamond",
D: "Oval",
answer: "D. Oval",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Movement of data from point A to point B will be",
A: "broadcast to all nodes.",
B: "done through a multicast.",
C: "terminated in the middle of the link.",
D: "done through point-to-point transmission.",
answer: "A. broadcast to all nodes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The computer at Q1 broke down. The possible effects on the network will be that",
A: "the whole network will break down.",
B: "the terminators will not be require",
C: "the network will continue to work.",
D: "only the left part of the network will break down.",
answer: "C. the network will continue to work. (In a bus topology, if one node fails, it usually doesn't affect the entire network.)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following reasons does not justify the use of a layered approach to networking?",
A: "Allow for large networking",
B: "Makes creation of networks easy",
C: "Allows many programmers to implement a network",
D: "Permits computers on different platforms to communicate",
answer: "A. Allow for large networking (Layered networking actually facilitates large and complex networks.)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Communication facilities owned and operated by a common carrier that serve a large number of subscribers is called",
A: "private network.",
B: "public network.",
C: "public-private network.",
D: "value-added network.",
answer: "B. public network.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A home page is",
A: "the initial page of a website.",
B: "the website users visit most times",
C: "web page created by an individual.",
D: "a web page a user eventually reach by clicking a series of hyperlinks",
answer: "A. the initial page of a website.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The logical operator used when selecting records in a database that always meet two provided criteria is",
A: "AND",
B: "IF",
C: "NOT.",
D: "OR.",
answer: "A. AND",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A simultaneous two-way video and audio transmission over multiple locations is called",
A: "conference call.",
B: "telecommuting.",
C: "television.",
D: "video conferencing.",
answer: "D. video conferencing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A kilobyte is equal to",
A: "512 bytes.",
B: "1021 bytes.",
C: "1000 bytes.",
D: "1024 bytes.",
answer: "D. 1024 bytes.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The binary number 101.0110 2 converts to decimal as",
A: "1.357.",
B: "1.375.",
C: "5.357.",
D: "5.375.",
answer: "B. 5.375.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. What will be the result of writing the formula = today () + 7 in a worksheet of a spreadsheet if the current calendar date is 14 August, 1960?",
A: "7 August, 1960",
B: "21 August, 1953",
C: "21 August, 1960",
D: "21 August, 1967",
answer: "C. 21 August, 1960",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. To calculate the products of all the numbers in the worksheet application in Figure 2, use the formula",
A: "= PRODUCTS (A : C1).",
B: "= PRODUCT (A1 : C4).",
C: "= PRODUCTS (C1 : A1).",
D: "= PRODUCT (A1 : E4).",
answer: "B. = PRODUCT (A1 : C4).",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. To calculate the average of all the numbers in the worksheet application in Figure 2, use the formula",
A: "= AVERAGE (A1 : B4).",
B: "= AVERAGE (A4 : C4).",
C: "= AVERAGE (C4 : Al).",
D: "= PRODUCT (A1 : C4) / 12.",
answer: "D. = PRODUCT (A1 : C4) / 12.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. If today’s date is 02/02/2018. What will be the result of typing = today () + 1 in a cell of a spreadsheet?",
A: "02/03/2018",
B: "03/02/2018",
C: "03/03/2019",
D: "02/02/2019",
answer: "B. 03/02/2018",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. When a user encounters the command DIM A (3, 12) in a QBASIC program, it means",
A: "the third item in the array A is assigned the value 12.",
B: "the array A is dimensioned to hold 312 items of data",
C: "the array A is dimensioned to hold 36 items of data",
D: "an error message will be displayed on-screen.",
answer: "C. the array A is dimensioned to hold 36 items of data",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. To print the 100th item of the array K in a QBASIC program, use the command",
A: "PRINT K*100.",
B: "PRINT K(100).",
C: "PRINT “K(100)»",
D: "PRINT 100",
answer: "B. PRINT K(100).",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following BASIC commands demonstrates the correct way of coding the statement: “Dimension the array R to hold 20 string variables”?",
A: "LET R $=20",
B: "LET R = 20",
C: "DIM R$ (20)",
D: "DIM R (20)",
answer: "C. DIM R$ (20)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. How many values will be printed from the following QBASIC codes? LET C= 0 DO WHILE C < 12 INPUT P PRINT P LET C=C+ 1 LOOP",
A: "One string value",
B: "One integer value",
C: "Twelve string values",
D: "Twelve integer values",
answer: "D. Twelve integer values",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. How many records are in the table Honda Parts?",
A: "5",
B: "10",
C: "11",
D: "50",
answer: "C. 11 (Based on the provided table image, there are 11 records.)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The data type for the field Unit Price in the table Honda Parts is",
A: "Currency.",
B: "Number.",
C: "OLE object.",
D: "Text.",
answer: "B. Number",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The data type for the field Quantity On Hand in the table Honda Parts is",
A: "Auto Number.",
B: "Currency.",
C: "Number.",
D: "Text.",
answer: "C. Number",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A company introduced new software that the IT staff are not conversant with. As the IT manager, which of the following advice would you give the company owner for optimal performance?",
A: "Employ more staff",
B: "Sack and employ new staff",
C: "Discourage the use of the software",
D: "Retrain the staff to use the new software",
answer: "D. Retrain the staff to use the new software",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]